{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": " Molar mass of styrene is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "104.15 g/mol",
        "b": "106 g/mol",
        "c": "28 g/mol",
        "d": "78.96 g/mol"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "During a step growth polymerization,what would happen for an addition polymerisation ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Monomer molecules are still present in the final polymer.",
        "b": "Monomer breaks down to form free radicals.",
        "c": "Monomer breaks down to form ions.",
        "d": "Monomer disappears early in the reaction."
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "  A co polymer can be found by:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Polymerising two different monomers",
        "b": "Polymerising two identical monomers",
        "c": "Mixing two different polymers",
        "d": " mixing two identical polymers"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
       {
      "question": " The effect of chain transfer reagents is to:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increase the average degree of polymerization",
        "b": "Reduce average degree of polymerization",
        "c": " Increase the rate of polymerisation",
        "d": "Reduce the rate of polymerisation"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
     {
      "question": " In ionic polymerisation 'living Polymer' is formed when",
      "answers": {
        "a": " termination reactions do not occur",
        "b": "propagation reactions do not occur",
        "c": "initiation reactions occur faster than termination reactions",
        "d": "Amino acids are used as monomers"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
     {
      "question": "The free radical polymerisation, inhibitors",
      "answers": {
        "a": "stop the formation of free radicals",
        "b": "increase the average degree of polymerisation",
        "c": "Increase the rate of polymerisation",
        "d": "Reduce average degree of polymerisation"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
      {
      "question": "The free radical polymerisation, inhibitors",
      "answers": {
        "a": "stop the formation of free radicals",
        "b": "increase the average degree of polymerisation",
        "c": "Increase the rate of polymerisation",
        "d": "Reduce average degree of polymerisation"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
      {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a natural polymer",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Silk",
        "b": "Starch",
        "c": "Nylon",
        "d": "protein"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
      {
      "question": "the monomer that is polymerized to make natural rubber is______________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "melamine",
        "b": "ethylene",
        "c": "isoprene",
        "d": "adipic acid"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
      {
      "question": "as a polymer becomes more crystalline_____________",
      "answers": {
        "a": " its melting point decreases",
        "b": "its density decreases",
        "c": " its yield stress decreases",
        "d": "none of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
      {
      "question": "In the context of biopolymers ,the opposite of the polymerization process is___",
      "answers": {
        "a": "sublimation",
        "b": "condensation",
        "c": "hydrolysis",
        "d": " addition"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
      {
      "question": "the monomer that is polymerized to make natural rubber is",
      "answers": {
        "a": " melamine",
        "b": "formaldehyde",
        "c": "ethylene",
        "d": "isoprene"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
      {
      "question": "the formation of a condensation polymer generally involves_____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "the addition of a plasticizer",
        "b": "the mixing of sulfur with an addition polymer",
        "c": "the elimination of a small molecule",
        "d": "the vaporization of a plasticizer"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
       {
      "question": "which of the following,only______is an addition polymer",
      "answers": {
        "a": "polystyrene",
        "b": "polyurethane",
        "c": "polycarbonate",
        "d": "nylon"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
       {
      "question": "the empirical formula of an addition polymer______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "is the same as that of the monomer from which it is formed except that 2 H and 1 O have been added",
        "b": "is the same as that of the monomer from which it is formed except that 2 H and 1 O have been subtracted",
        "c": "is the same as that of the monomer from which it is formed",
        "d": " is the same as that of the monomer from which it is formed except that 2 H and 1 C have been added"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
